DANIEL O'BRIEN, ESQUIRE

danielobrien@coastalparametrics.com daniel.obrien@alumni.vanderbilt.edu

Active Secret/Former TS/SCI clearance

SENIOR-LEVEL EXECUTIVE CORPORATE STRATEGY, DEVELOPMENT AND IMPLEMENTATION

PROFILE & VALUE

Effective and accountable in high-profile executive roles-

Experienced, developer and facilitator of corporate strategic initiatives originating from a unique breadth and depth of business, legal and technical credentials. Overcome complex business challenges and effect high-stakes decisions using experience-backed judgment, strong work ethic combined with irreproachable integrity and tactfulness.

Corporate Strategy & Development Specialist-

Characterized as a visionary strategist and tactician. Consistent record of delivering extraordinary organic and inorganic results in revenue growth, operational performance, and profitability.

Consistently deliver mission-critical results-

Driven by a visceral "hard-wired" need to strategize, to innovate, and to disprove the words "It can't be done!" Gifted with the vision, design, process reengineering, turnaround management, and reorganization. Innovative investments made using data, instincts, insight, judgment, and timing.

Respect and leverage human capital-

Passionate Leader who can maintain confident deportment and calm demeanor for orderly decisive results in chaotic environments. Motivator who can mentor and lead talented professionals, direct cross-functional teams using interactive and inspirational leadership that spurs people to willingly give 110% effort and loyalty and live the culture and lead by example.

Strong orientations in operations and finance-

Participate in high-level operational initiatives, including infrastructure design, process reengineering, turnaround management, and reorganization. Recognized as the "go-to" person for difficult analysis and problem solving capabilities

QUALIFICATIONS & EXPERTISE

Vision, Strategy, Execution & Leadership

Mergers, Acquisitions & Divestitures

Mobile: (774) 261-3174

Corporate & Business Development

Startup, Turnaround, and Change

Due Diligence, Deal Structuring & Negotiations

Financial & Legal Transactions

Intellectual Property Management

Technologist

Government Relations

Product Development & Rollout

Quality & Continuous Improvement

Investor, Analyst & Board Relations

Executive Advisory & Decision Support

International

Relationship Building

RECENT BENCHMARKS & MILESTONES

- As President and founder, architected and superintended business targeting critical maritime infrastructure
 protection while simultaneously securing U.S. Navy resource sponsorship (OPNAV N852), establishing
 Congressional support and forging key partnerships with The U.S. Naval Warfare Laboratory (NSWC
 PCD), The Stevens Institute's National Maritime and Port Security Center of Excellence and The New
 York Police Department's Counterterrorism Office.
- As Director working for the President, provided corporate business and Intellectual Property (IP) counsel for defense, homeland security, medical, synthetic vision, operating system and security software, semiconductor and telecommunications market segments spearheading organic and inorganic investments that contributed to a cumulative annual growth rate (CAGR) of greater than 25% and 80% gross margins. Authored, instituted and managed corporate alliance and acquisition processes for a deal flow pipeline of over \$100 million in acquired and alliance transactions.

CAREER SNAPSHOT

LAW OFFICE OF DANIEL R. O'BRIEN, ESQ., Sterling, MA	2011 - Presen
Attorney	
AVIATION & AEROSPACE SERVICES, INC., Milton, DE	2011 - Present
Board of Directors	
COASTAL PARAMETRICS/ASSETT COASTAL SURVEILLANCE, Sterling, MA/Manassas, VA	2006 - 2011
President and CEO	
MERCURY COMPUTER SYSTEMS, INC., Chelmsford, MA	2000 - 2006
Director of Corporate Development/Strategic Technology Initiatives	
ROBERTS & O'BRIEN, PLLP, Nashville, TN	1998 - 2000
Partner - Attorney	
FISH & RICHARDSON, P.C., Boston, MA	1997 - 1998
IP Attorney	
SAIC/DARPA, Arlington, VA	1996 - 1997
Program Manager Air Defense Technology Division (Liaison to DARPA)	
Continuation of program research from MIT	
MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Lexington, MA	1989 - 1993
Lead Researcher Lincoln Laboratory	
THERMO ELECTRON TECHNOLOGIES, Waltham, MA	1987 - 1989
Project Leader and Junior Program Manager Research and Development Center	

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>LAW OFFICE OF DANIEL R. O'BRIEN, ESQ.</u>, Sterling, MA *Attorney*

2011 - Present

• Law practice providing counsel and representation on a variety of business practice areas. Although the core of the practice focuses on U.S. law, the firm also advises and handles the international implications of business law issues pertaining investment and incubation of new enterprises overseas.

<u>AVIATION & AEROSPACE SERVICES, INC.</u>, Milton, DE *Board of Directors*

2011 - Present

• Lead organizational structuring efforts for the creation of a \$30M Maintenance, Repair and Overhaul (MRO) commercial aviation facility in the Middle East. Provide tactical guidance for high-level issues such as to raising capitol, partnership formation, international government relations and capital investment. Brief and respond to the foreign government officials at the secretary level to ensure continued support and governmental approvals. Determine the company's vision and mission to guide and set the pace for its initial operations and future development. Identification of, and negotiation with, target technology companies to acquire to incubate a new business overseas.

COASTAL PARAMETRICS/ASSETT COASTAL SURVEILLANCE, Sterling, MA/Manassas, VA 2006 – 2011 **President and CEO**

- Established strategy and tactically executed plan to cultivate new business under severe budget, personnel, schedule and administration change challenges by securing Congressional, DoD OPNAV resource, Navy program office, and National Laboratory sponsorships, instituted technology alliances with the U.S. Center of Excellence for port security and NYPD's Office of Counterterrorism, and created DoD prime contractor alliance channel relationships.
- Succeeded in identification of, and negotiation and closure with, a synergistic technology and venture provider to incubate a new subsidiary business.

Daniel R. O'Brien Esq.

• Firmed parent organization's corporate rudder by evaluating and strategically persuading executive staff to recognize constraints of business structure and to change business model to leverage core competencies bringing the \$10 million business on track to secure multiple contracts on a plan for growth.

MERCURY COMPUTER SYSTEMS, INC., Chelmsford, MA

2004 - 2006

Director of Strategic Technology Initiatives - President's Office

- Lead strategist/corporate officer and business plan author for the creation of port security and critical infrastructure protection company to address the Homeland Security Market (Coastal Parametrics).
- Instrumental in creating and growing Signals Intelligence (SIGINT) Business Unit. This BU grew to over \$70 million in revenues in five years becoming Mercury's largest revenue generating business unit.
- Lead strategist/corporate officer and business plan author for several new businesses including, a Multi-Core software business (Softscale) with specialization in Multi-Independent level of Security (MILS), an integrated multi-intelligence SIGINT business (Ceptor) and the Federal Systems Subsidiary.
- One of four key executives appointed to re-orientate corporate strategy and execute cost measures in response to loss of significant revenue due to program cancellations in \$150 million business segment.
- Repurposed \$20 million in technology investments after analyzing the existing business case, technology strategy and resource allocation resulting in a \$50 million acquisition to capture majority market share.
- Cultivated and lead external strategic activities (alliances through mergers and acquisitions), including identification of targets based on their value propositions, competitive advantages, innovative capacity and organizational capabilities. Perform detailed commercial, financial and strategic analysis as well as determine both strategic and operational fit.

MERCURY COMPUTER SYSTEMS, INC., Chelmsford, MA

2000 - 2004

Director of Corporate Development

- Identified and acquired a three letter agency sponsored *Disruptive Technology* company based on patented direct digital synthesizer for ultra high performance radio frequency (RF) equipment targeted to the intelligence community providing opportunity to enter technical arena unmatched technology advantage against entrenched incumbents.
- Developed concept and initiated integrated product partnership with industry leading technology provider resulting in the development the Vita 57 Digital IF standard. VITA 57 is a new interconnect standard for passing a radio's digitized intermediate frequency data between system elements.
- Identified and secured a strategic alliance that kept Mercury from being designed out of their next generation medical products protecting \$30 million in revenue by identifying and initiating a corporate alliance with a high-end image processing company to facilitate an integrated display-processing subsystem to support our largest medical customer.
- Co-Sponsor Software Defined Radio initiative leading to Mercury chairing the standards effort for the Joint Tactical Radio Service's software communications architecture (SCA).
- Drafted market entry acquisition strategy for wireless base station communications market which if followed would have transformed Mercury into a \$1 billion plus wireless intellectual property supplier for 3G and beyond markets.

ROBERTS & O'BRIEN, PLLP, Nashville, TN

1998- 2000

Co-founder and Partner

Protected clients' rights by fully serving their needs in state, federal and U.S. Bankruptcy courts concentrating on business law and Federal Bankruptcy appellate litigation.

FISH & RICHARDSON, P.C., Boston, MA Attorney

1997 – 1998

Attorney practicing Intellectual Property law including technology transfer agreements, CRADAs, licenses, joint ventures, patent prosecution, know-how, trademark, legal research, and FCC regulations.

<u>SCIENCE APPLICATIONS INTERNATIONAL CORPORATION</u>, Arlington, VA 1996-1997 **Program Manager** Air Defense Technology Division (Continuation of program work from MIT below)

Program Manager to DARPA's Sensor Technology Office for conceptual evaluation and oversight of several varied advanced sensor technology programs. Responsible for the evaluation of SBIR Phase 1, 2 and 3 proposals obtained in response to DARPA solicitations to select high quality innovative research and development activities to solve defense-related scientific problems and stimulate technological innovation, especially those which have a high potential for commercialization in the private sector.

MASSACHUSETTS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Lexington, MA

1989 - 1993

Lead Researcher Lincoln Laboratory

Lead researcher in the development of the central component of an Airborne Electro-Optic Sensor (Classified). Liaison for a technology transfer initiative between the laboratory and five U.S. prime defense contractors. Invented a novel launch technique for optical intensity phase modulators, solving a twenty-year old design problem. Supervised the Optical Systems Engineering Group's electro-optic research laboratory. Lectured and published papers. Granted U.S. Patent 5,059,763.

THERMO ELECTRON TECHNOLOGIES, Waltham, MA

1987 - 1989

Project Leader and Junior Program Manager Research and Development Center,

Project Leader and Junior Program Manager for the development of Infrared Simulation systems. Tasks included development and computer analysis of mechanical structures, optics and infrared sources qualified to meet military specifications. Familiarity with light weighted optics and exotic composite materials to be used in airborne environments.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University School of Law, Nashville, TN (Self Financed Full Time Curriculum)

Doctor of Jurisprudence, 1996 Phi Delta Phi Honor Fraternity, President 1995-96, Vice President 1994-95 Intellectual Property Society, Federalist Society, American Bar Association

Central New England College, Westborough, MA

Bachelor of Science Electrical Engineering, 1986

Magna Cum Laude (Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society)

Framingham State College, Framingham, MA

Bachelor of Science Geophysics, 1983

RECOMMENDATION

The Honorable Dale Gerry

Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Navy (Retired) 4708 Tecumseh Street College Park, MD 20740 Office: (301) 345-5411